とにかく考えろ！ 思い付いたら動け！
Yes. Right now, they should be
spending every second training.
いいのか？ マジで私物化するぞ。
End x And x Beginning
うん　ん…。
What? He didn't have to worry about that... Weren't you happy that Kurapika
was leaving Yorknew City?
ん　ん…。
Sure, but he left without telling us.
あ　お兄ちゃんだ。
It's from Zepile. He said that you'll see him again.
うん。 ここ　どこ？
Yeah, and he recovered your
hundred million, as promised.
病院だよ。
He really did...
お兄ちゃんの友達が 病気で寝てるんだ。
Now you can buy back
your Hunter License. Yeah... Zepile-san really is special.
元の… 元気な姿に戻してやりたいんだ。
Man, that Hunter License is a real gem.
ナニカに代わるのね。
The pawn shop forked over a
hundred million on the spot. In a proper auction, you could
probably add two zeros...
ちぇだ！　せっかく お兄ちゃんといるのにな！
I know!
大丈夫　言っただろ。
I should become a pro Hunter
so I can sell the license...
これからは　ずっと一緒だよ。 約束だ。
I could live off the interest alone.
And forget about debt! Okay, then let's get crackin'!
頼むよ。
And start prepping for the Hunter Exam!
やっぱりだ キルアにだけは ルールが当てはまらない
#16 wins Greed Island for 60.2 billion.
これが　キルアだからなのか
Thank you very much.
直す「お願い」の後だからなのかは 検証が必要だけど
60.2 billion.. That's insane. And he won all seven copies.
[TEL]　うん　分かったよ。 どちらにせよ 壊せて直せる能力は
But it cost him half of his wealth.
飼いならせれば 強力無比な道具になる…
Recently, an unknown party
stole a copy of Greed Island won at auction for 30.5 billion by Mr. Battera.
まがまがしく　無機質で
But, not to be discouraged, yesterday he
won another copy for 27.8 billion, and another today for 60.2 billion.
殺し道からすら外れた 邪な野心を…
He must have some reason
to go so far for this game.
むごいことだよ… 操られてた頃のほうが 苦しまないなんて…
I've heard that upon clearing the game,
you receive a treasure map. Or a giant dragon appears
to grant your wish.
ナニカが眠っている時だけ アルカは起きる
Mr. Battera was able to acquire
all the copies of Greed Island. He's also seeking players,
but today's the deadline!
アルカの時間は 長いようで短い
There's already an amazing
line outside the venue.
ナニカの「おねだり」が失敗して 人が死んだ後
I apologize for keeping everyone waiting.
ナニカが次の誰かに
We will now begin selecting the players.
レベル１の「おねだり」を するまでの間…
As everyone already knows, you must be able to use Nen for this game.
ナニカに 「おねだり」されている誰かが
The test will proceed as follows.
途中で　ナニカの元から離れて
First, we need each applicant
to demonstrate their Nen.
「おねだり」が 中断されている間… ナニカが 何かを治して眠った後
We will then make our decision.
誰かがアルカに「お願い」をして それが　かなうまでの間…
The judge will be the
pro Hunter, Mr. Tsezgerra! The Money Hunter Tsezgerra!
一番いいのは この「お願い」を最後に
This game must pay big dividends.
もう　ナニカに何も 「お願い」しないことなのだろう
Let us begin the test. One at a time, come up
and show me your Ren.
頼む…。 ナニカ…　ゴンを治してくれ！
I'm certain they're judging
us on the entire process.
あい！
Approximately two hundred are in the hall.
何というパワー
I'm talking about the ones still in line and those waiting nearby.
中で　何が… 一体　誰が？
Especially the ones
standing next to the line. They're probably waiting
for someone to return, so they can ask what's inside.
何だ!?　これは…
That is why I must be careful
when selecting players. I get it!
いいのか？　いいのか？
Exactly.
マジで私物化するぞ…。
It's been over ten years,
and no one's cleared the game.
フフフ…。 ハハハハハ…。
Anyone worthwhile either
got in line at once, or figured out the trick and stayed in
their seats to focus, like we did.
素晴らしい！ ハハハハハ…。
Wouldn't you agree, kid?
ハハハハハ…　ハハハハハ…！
Gon? You realized what was going on?
ハハハハ　ハハハハハ…！ これは　ぜひとも欲しい… これは…
Well, it was just a hunch. I thought it was only natural that the hosts
would want to test everyone here.
俺のものだ！
That's true.
ハハハハハ…！
You win, kid. Yeah, I'm impressed. Not many people can stick to their ideals.
何か　あらためて訴えたいことは ありますでしょうか？ なければ　このまま　すぐ 最終投票に入りますが？
The steeper and more dangerous the path, the greater the need for both wit
and ignorance to move forward. Next, please.
無駄よ！ 今度こそ　何を言っても！
My name is Puhat. Nice to meet you.
まぁ… 大勢は決まった気もしますが
People who act smart usually fail.
せっかくですから レオリオさんに伺いましょう。
He can hear you.
ん？ もう一度　聞かせてください。
But he's right.
会長になったら　何をするか。
I was too focused on logically
deducing the best method.
それでは　レオリオさん あらためまして　お答えください。
I'm heading over. Yep, good luck.
会長になったら　何をしますか？
If I want to advance,
I'll have to take risks.
ゴンを助ける！
Because I've chosen a dangerous path!
そのために お前ら全員　動いてもらう！ 以上だ。
Listen to me... Never take risks.
このタイミングが 一番だったんだけど…
Act only when success is guaranteed.
まぁ　やっぱり 僕は「カミサマ」じゃ　ない
Otherwise, wait. Waiting is our most crucial job.
それでは　人事や組織再編成など 今後の構想などは　ありますか？ は？
If victory isn't assured, revealing your
strength is the most foolish move to make.
あるわけねえだろ　そんなもん！
That's how my old man operates.
ぶっちゃけ　俺は　何で ここに立っているのかさえ
But I'm no longer an assassin.
よく分かってねえんだ！
I'm a Hunter!
アハハハ…　そうですよね。
Let me see your Ren.
僕からの質問は以上です。
Can I show you my Hatsu instead?
無駄よ　パリストン 皆　そんなこと 十分　分かった上で
That's fine. You're free to show me anything
that demonstrates your power.
レオリオに票を入れている
Prove that the Ren I saw previously
支持者が全員でサポートする つもりだからこその 拍手だったのだから…
didn't represent your true power. Then, I'll get started.
分かりました！
He changed his aura into electricity!
では　これより 緊急動議を発令いたします！
In theory, it's certainly possible...
はい？
that he learned this from
scratch in four days!
えっと　何言ってんの？ 緊急動議です！
Well? Need to see more?
これから　皆さんには
No, that's enough. You pass.
「ハンター十ヶ条」の 第八条　九条にのっとって
Yes!
信任投票をしていただきます！
However, this technique could not
テーマは　「ハンター十ヶ条」と ハンター試験の見直しです。 まずは　現行のハンター試験制度の 撤廃を提案いたします！
have fully developed overnight. You'd require years of
torturous training,
exposing your body to strong electricity. Who are you?
ん！
Strong electricity?
撤廃に賛成の方はマルを 反対の方はバツを！
From birth, I've been
exposed to electricity.
ちょっと待った！
Family reasons.
違うって　ばか寅！
Seven people...
確かに　その通り！ 閣議は多数決で　１１対１。
That guy was right.
十ヶ条の改変に賛成したのは 僕だけでしたねぇ。
The people who passed are those
who moved immediately or waited in their seats.
この壇上に　チードルさんか ミザイストムさんが残っていれば
Well, I wonder if Gon will be okay.
しかし　２人とも脱落し ここに　いません！
Gon.
そして　レオリオさんは 組閣について
Killua!
全くの白紙だと言っています。
Good, you got chosen.
「十二支ん」としてではなく
Of course.
僕が副会長として　単独に 意見を述べられるタイミングは
Was that boom your doing? Uh-huh.
ここしかないのです！
Honestly...
お分かりですか？　カンザイさん！
Those kids are scary.
今　ここが 唯一のタイミングなのですよ！
Well, allow me to congratulate you.
クッ…。
The twenty-one people
here have earned the
もちろん 第八条を強く振りかざせば 閣議の決定を無視して 強制動議は可能です。
right to play Greed Island. Upon clearing the game,
you will receive 50 billion Jenny.
しかし　それは　したくなかった。 「十二支ん」は　前会長の 大切な形見なのですから！
The details are in the contract, so read and sign it before
you depart at 5 PM.
おい　余計なこと言うと
Cheers!
こいつ １０倍にして返して来るぞ！
You've made it past the first stage.
うぅ…。
Could you look at this for us?
できるならば このまま波風を立てずに
What is it?
済ませたい自分も　正直います。
A contract?
だが　しかし！　しかしながら
Looks like it can be summarized in three points.
故テラデインさんやブシドラさんの主張は もっともです！
First, you can't file any claims
if you're injured or die.
十ヶ条の三や四！
Second, any items that you bring out
現行の試験による弊害は深刻だと 言わざるを得ないでしょう！
of the game belong to Mr. Battera.
あいつは 勝とうと思っていない
Third, if you clear the game, you will receive a
50-billion Jenny reward.
負けようとも思っていない
I don't see any problems. Yep!
その通りだわ
So once you sign it, you're good to go.
何て嫌な奴
That second point seems important.
勝ち負けなんか 眼中にないから
"Anything that you
bring out of the game."
損得勘定抜きで 無機質　かつ冷静に
That's why he's paying the big bucks.
他者の感情を操り ルールを利用して
Anything? Like what? I'm willing to hand it over.
私達が最も嫌がることを 選択できるのだ
I'm not looking for items. I just want to get closer to Ging!
はい　何でしょう？
See ya. Good luck on your exam, Leorio.
私は　レオリオ氏が勝った場合 参謀に立候補します。
Yeah, you guys be careful. Next time we see you,
you'll be a doctor.
その際　十ヶ条とハンター試験を
Wouldn't that mean we won't see
each other for at least four years?
抜本的に見直すと ここで約束します。
We plan to clear the
game much more quickly.
宙に浮いたテラデインの票を 削ろうとしても無駄よ！
I don't intend to fall behind.
ゴン!!
I'm going to trust him! I'll use my own card.
うお!!
Then put the ring on,
and start the game. Gon.
チクショ!! 心配したぞ!!
Wait in the starting
area until I get there.
グッ…。 よかった!! 本当に　よかった!!
Once you see a "Now Playing" message,
the next person can begin.
ああ　そうだな！　うんうん。
Welcome to Greed Island.
ん？
I will now explain how the game works.
ハハっ　みんな お前を心配してくれてたんだよ。 あっ　ども…　ども…。
Book and Gain. Place the hand with the ring in
front of you, and say, "Book." Book.
パリストンが最後まで 残したかったのは　レオリオ
In this game, your task is
to collect certain cards.
これで…
That book is for storing the
cards you've collected.
レオリオが会長をする動機も 後押しも消滅した！
Please look at the first page.
お前が会長やれ！ レオリオ キルアがゴンを治したことは
Each slot is labeled with a number.
ゴンには　絶対　黙っててくれ。
You can only place cards of the
same number in these slots.
え？　何でだよ。
These are your "restricted slots."
絶対だ！
Please flip ahead a few pages.
キルアのため　約束してくれ。
Wait, there aren't any numbers!
あ…　ああ　分かったよ。
Yes, you may place any
card inside these slots.
パリストン…　いつ？
These are your "free slots."
一体　いつから　こうなることを 予測して動いてたの？
There are 100 restricted slots,
numbered 0 to 99.
はい？　いやいや… そんな能力　僕にはありませんよ。
Then, you have another 45 free slots.
こうなったのは　たまたまです。
To clear this game, you must
fill the 100 restricted slots.
お願い…　知りたいの。 悔しいけど…　完敗だから！
I just need to collect a hundred cards? Yes. Specifically, you must
transform one hundred items
ジンさんが…
into cards and put them in your book. Transform them?
立候補するって言った時ですよ。 え？
For example, if you obtain a sword, it will become a card
the moment you get it.
僕が挑発したら　ジンさんは 「ゴンは死なない」って 言ったでしょ？
If you wish to use a card as the item,
you must use the spell "Gain." Gain...
その時 頭の中に浮かんだんです。 今の　この場面が…。
a card to item form, you can never transform it into a card again. If you want to make it a card again,
you must reacquire the item. Do you understand everything so far?
まぁ　壇上に立っているのは ジンさんと僕で
Yeah, basically... There are two other cases in which
勝ったのはジンさんでしたけどね。
you cannot transform
an item into a card.
頭の中では。
The first is when you reach the item's
まず　ジンさんが 「死なない」って断言した以上
maximum card transformation limit. Card transformation limit?
ゴンくんを治す方法は あるんだと確信しました。
Yes, every item in this game has
a card transformation limit.
そして　彼を選挙に利用されたら 僕は決して 勝てないと思いました。 分かりますか？
For example, if an item has a
transformation limit of three, and three players have already
あの時　僕は すでに完敗してるんです。
transformed the item into a card, the fourth to find it will be
unable to change it into a card.
レオリオさんが登場して ジンさん　殴って 演説で「仲間が命懸けで　ゴンくんを 助けようとしてる」って聞いて
In the second case... Huh? If you don't place the card into
your book within one minute, it will automatically revert to an item. In this case, as well, you can never transform
that item into a card again.
ようやく　この絵は完成しました。
Do you understand?
勝利を確信したのは　さっきです。
Yeah, kinda... Finally, the most important note...
仲間がゴンくんを助けたんだって 直感しました。
I can't remember all of this... If a player dies, their book and ring are destroyed
後は　本人がここに来るまで 粘るだけ。
and the book's contents are lost.
あっ　動議は取り下げますので ご心配なく。
Does it matter anymore if you're dead? That concludes my explanation.
見たこともない誰かを 信用したっていうの？
You'll need to learn everything else
about the game by playing it.
あなたが!?
Uh-huh, got it. Thanks.
僕は　ジンさんを 敵として信頼してます。
I wish you the best of luck.
そのジンさんが
Please take those stairs.
信じますよ。
Loading save data.
決まってるじゃないですか！
I have a message from Ging Freecss.
今から立候補しろ！ そしたら　お前に入れるぞ！
But if you expected a clue to my
location, you're out of luck.
ステージで何か話せ！
I just wanted to show
off this game to you.
スピーチ！　スピーチ！
It doesn't matter what brought you here.
いや　参ったな。
Because you won't be able to leave
あっ…。
until you obtain a specific item.
ジン？
the legendary game Greed Island.
うん　実にヤバい！
A new adventure is about to begin.